JONATHAN TAYLOR

SUMMARY

Diligent, detail-oriented, open-source-contributing computer science graduate with 7+ years of experience working with Java and 2+ years of experience working with frontend web technologies. I am a great listener with great interpersonal skills. I will put a smile on your face. Expect a faithful, morale-boosting self-learner eager to make an impact to all who rely on him.

CONTACT

+12054347006

jontaylor091@gmail.com

Pelham, Alabama, 35124

linkedin.com/in/jonathan-taylor-746ba8195/

github.com/Jtmonument

EDUCATION

Troy University B.Sc. Computer Science Minor in Cyber Security August 2018 - May 2022

GPA: 3.3

RELEVANT COURSES

Software Engineering CS-3332-XTIA

 SDLC, Scrum, Agile, loose coupling, DevOps, extreme programming, pair programming

Analysis of Algorithms CS-3329-TSAA

 Time complexity, space complexity, dynamic programming, graph theory, shortest-path algorithms

Cyber Security Technique & Practice CS-4455-TSAA

 VirtualBox, Kali Linux (virtual machine), nmap, pentbox (honeypot), iptables, pfSense, wireshark, snort (IDS), firewall-builder, scapy

Data Structures CS-3323-TSAA

 Arrays, linked lists, stacks, queues, trees, binary search trees, searching and sorting algorithms

SKILLS

Programming Languages

- Java [Very Proficient] (7+ years of experience)
- Python [Limited Proficiency]

Soft Skills

- Problem solving
- Team-plaver
- Time management
- Intercultural
- Excellent communication
- Object-Oriented Programming Design
- SOLID principles
- French Language

Other technologies

- Intellij [Very Proficient] (5+ years of experience)
- Spring Framework (JPA, Web, HATEOAS & more)
- Maven
- Unit Testing (JUnit)
- Linux
- Selenium
- Frontend tech: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Server-side tech: MySQL, PHP

CERTIFICATIONS

- Introduction to DevOps
- Introduction to Containers w/ Docker, Kubernetes & OpenShift
- Introduction to Cloud Computing
- Getting Started with Git and GitHub

PROJECTS

Open-source Algorithms

GitHub: TheAlgorithms/Java

• Topological Sort PR #3060, JUnit5

List of Spring Projects

GitHub: Jtmonument/spring-repos

REST API with an MVC, Pet Clinic website, Web Application

"McRonalds" Restaurant Database

GitHub: Jtmonument/sql-database-project

 Using MySQL and MySQL Workbench created a database with effective functions, triggers, and EER Diagrams

Japan Travel Website

GitHub: Jtmonument/japan-travel-website

 Using PHP, SQL, XAMPP, HTML, CSS, JS, I created the #1 UI in my class with good server-side scripting

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer / Master

Troy University Computer Science Club

December 2021 - May 2022

 managing the Computer Science club website and club activities

Student AV / Tech Assistant Workship

Troy University

January 2020 - September 2020

Setting up technical equipment for university events

AuburnHackathon

Auburn University

February 2020

 creating a game in C++ that enables players to disturb PC functionality

TroyHackathon

Troy University Computer Science Department

January 2020

• team project working on frontend page templates for a pet adoption website

Cashier/Cook

McAlister's Deli

June 2017 - Present

• serving guests with good customer service and faithfully preparing items on the menu